YOONJOO LEE

voonjoo.lee@kaist.ac.kr | voonjoolee.com

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI) and natural language processing (NLP). I aim to support people to learn from and make sense of dense information (e.g., content in lecture videos and scientific articles) by structuring the information in the context to create adaptive scaffoldings (e.g., QAs, dialogues, explanations) using AI models.

EDUCATION

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science. Advisor: Juho Kim

Sep. 2020 – Present

Mar. 2018 – Feb. 2020

Seoul, Republic of Korea **Ewha Womans University**

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics). Advisor: Dongwan Shin B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics

Graduated with Honors (Magna Cum Laude)

Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA, USA Exchange student in Mathematics Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

PUBLICATIONS

Conference and Journal Papers

[C7] QASA: Advanced Question Answering on Scientific Articles

Yoonjoo Lee*, Kyungjae Lee*, Sunghyun Park, Dasol Hwang, Jaehyeon Kim, Hong-in Lee, Moontae Lee ICML 2023: Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning

[C6] Cells, Generators, and Lenses: Design Framework for Object-Oriented Interaction with Large Language Models

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

UIST 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (to appear).

[C5] DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-Step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Sundong Kim, Yohan Yun, Juho Kim

CHI 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

[C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create **Effective Studying Environments**

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral **Efficiency**

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

Last Updated: November 3, 2023

[C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

Preprints

[A1] EvalLM: Interactive Evaluation of Large Language Model Prompts on User-Defined Criteria

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Juho Kim

Under Review, 2023

Posters and Workshop Papers

[P5] LMCanvas: Object-Oriented Interaction to Personalize Large Language Model-Powered Writing Environments

Tae Soo Kim, Arghya Sarkar, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, and Juho Kim

CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI

[P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

[P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, Yoonjoo Lee, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters

[P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

[P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Allen Institute for AI (AI2)

Seattle, US

Research Scientist Intern, Semantic Scholar Team May - Oct. 2023

Mentor: Pao Siangliulue, Joseph Chee Chang, Jonathan Bragg, Kyle Lo

LG AI Research Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern, Advanced Machine Learning Lab
Mentor: Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee
[C6]

KIXLAB, KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Intern Mar. 2020 – Aug. 2020

Mentor: Juho Kim, Jean Y. Song

Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group

Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019

Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park [P1, P2, C1, C2]

Undergraduate Research Intern, Data Sciences Group Jan. 2018 – Feb. 2018

Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

Last Updated: November 3, 2023

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

TEACHING

Introduction to Social Computing

KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

Fall 2020, Fall 2021

Time Series Analysis

Alysis Spring 2019

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin

Regression Analysis Fall 2018

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Program Committee

• CHI LBW 2023

Reviewer

- EMNLP 2023
- CHI 2024, 2023, 2022
- UIST 2022, 2023
- ACL 2023
- CSCW 2023
- C&C 2022
- IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

Student Volunteer

CHI 2022

INVITED TALKS

Invited Talk at UCSD Design Lab

Oct. 2023

Title: Adapting Scaffolding to Support Knowledge Consumption through Interactive AI-Driven Systems

Invited Talk at University of Washington

Oct. 2023

Title: Adapting Scaffolding to Support Knowledge Consumption through Interactive AI-Driven Systems

HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Research Assistant Scholarship

2019

College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

Admission Scholarship

2018

College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

Honors Scholarship

2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Dean's List

2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship

2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

SERVICE AND LEADERSHIP

KAIST-Google ExploreCSR

2022

Student Organizer

Programming Mentoring

2016 - 2017

Leader of Student Organizer

Last Updated: November 3, 2023